{
   "set_name": "LX103",
   "questions": [
{
	"question_number": 1
	,"question": "Which SysV init configuration file should be modified to disable the ctrl-alt-delete key combination?"
	,"choices": [
		"/etc/keys"
		,"/proc/keys"
		,"/etc/inittab"
		,"/proc/inittab"
		,"/etc/reboot"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 2
	,"question": "During a system boot cycle, what program is executed after the BIOS completes its tasks?"
	,"choices": [
		"The bootloader"
		,"The inetd program"
		,"The init program"
		,"The kernel"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 3
	,"question": "Which run levels should never be declared as the default run level when using SysV init? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"0"
		,"1"
		,"3"
		,"5"
		,"6"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AE"
}
,{
	"question_number": 4
	,"question": "Which of the following statements is correct when talking about /proc/?"
	,"choices": [
		"All changes to files in /proc/ are stored in /etc/proc.d/ and restored on reboot."
		,"All files within /proc/ are read-only and their contents cannot be changed."
		,"All changes to files in /proc/ are immediately recognized by the kernel."
		,"All files within /proc/ are only readable by the root user."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 5
	,"question": "What of the following statements are true regarding /dev/ when using udev? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"Entries for all possible devices get created on boot even if those devices are not connected."
		,"Additional rules for udev can be created by adding them to /etc/udev/rules.d/."
		,"When using udev, it is not possible to create block or character devices in /dev/ using mknod."
		,"The /dev/ directory is a filesystem of type tmpfs and is mounted by udev during system startup."
		,"The content of /dev/ is stored in /etc/udev/dev and is restored during system startup."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "BD"
}
,{
	"question_number": 6
	,"question": "Which of the following information is stored within the BIOS? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"Boot device order"
		,"Linux kernel version"
		,"Timezone"
		,"Hardware configuration"
		,"The system's hostname"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AD"
}
,{
	"question_number": 7
	,"question": "Which of the following commands reboots the system when using SysV init? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"shutdown -r now"
		,"shutdown -r \\\"rebooting\\\""
		,"telinit 6"
		,"telinit 0"
		,"shutdown -k now \\\"rebooting\\\""
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AC"
}
,{
	"question_number": 8
	,"question": "Which of the following are init systems used within Linux systems? (Choose THREE correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"startd"
		,"systemd"
		,"Upstart"
		,"SysInit"
		,"SysV init"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "BCE"
}
,{
	"question_number": 9
	,"question": "Which file in the /proc filesystem lists parameters passed from the bootloader to the kernel? (Specify the file name only without any path.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"cmdline"
		,"/proc/cmdline"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 10
	,"question": "What information can the lspci command display about the system hardware? (Choose THREE correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"Device IRQ settings"
		,"PCI bus speed"
		,"System battery type"
		,"Device vendor identification"
		,"Ethernet MAC address"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "ABD"
}
,{
	"question_number": 11
	,"question": "Which of the following commands brings a system running SysV init into a state in which it is safe to perform maintenance tasks? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"shutdown -R 1 now"
		,"shutdown -single now"
		,"init 1"
		,"telinit 1"
		,"runlevel 1"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "CD"
}
,{
	"question_number": 12
	,"question": "What is the first program that is usually started, at boot time, by the Linux kernel when using SysV init?"
	,"choices": [
		"/lib/init.so"
		,"/sbin/init"
		,"/etc/rc.d/rcinit"
		,"/proc/sys/kernel/init"
		,"/boot/init"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 13
	,"question": "Which command will display messages from the kernel that were output during the normal boot sequence?"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"dmesg"
		,"/bin/dmesg"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 14
	,"question": "Which of the following commands will write a message to the terminals of all logged in users?"
	,"choices": [
		"bcast"
		,"mesg"
		,"print"
		,"wall"
		,"yell"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 15
	,"question": "Which of the following kernel parameters instructs the kernel to suppress most boot messages?"
	,"choices": [
		"silent"
		,"verbose=0"
		,"nomesg"
		,"quiet"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 16
	,"question": "Which of the following options for the kernel's command line changes the systemd boot target to rescue.target instead of the default target?"
	,"choices": [
		"systemd.target=rescue.target"
		,"systemd.runlevel=rescue.target"
		,"systemd.service=rescue.target"
		,"systemd.default=rescue.target"
		,"systemd.unit=rescue.target"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "E"
}
,{
	"question_number": 17
	,"question": "After modifying GNU GRUB's configuration file, which command must be run for the changes to take effect?"
	,"choices": [
		"kill -HUP $(pidof grub)"
		,"grub-install"
		,"grub"
		,"No action is required"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 18
	,"question": "Which of the following commands is used to update the list of available packages when using dpkg based package management?"
	,"choices": [
		"apt-get update"
		,"apt-get upgrade"
		,"apt-cache update"
		,"apt-get refresh"
		,"apt-cache upgrade"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 19
	,"question": "Which of the following commands lists the dependencies of a given dpkg package?"
	,"choices": [
		"apt-cache depends-on package"
		,"apt-cache dependencies package"
		,"apt-cache depends package"
		,"apt-cache requires package"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 20
	,"question": "Which of the following options is used in a GRUB Legacy configuration file to define the amount of time that the GRUB menu will be shown to the user?"
	,"choices": [
		"hidemenu"
		,"splash"
		,"timeout"
		,"showmenu"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 21
	,"question": "What can the Logical Volume Manager (LVM) be used for? (Choose THREE correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"To create RAID 9 arrays."
		,"To dynamically change the size of logical volumes."
		,"To encrypt logical volumes."
		,"To create snapshots."
		,"To dynamically create or delete logical volumes."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "BDE"
}
,{
	"question_number": 22
	,"question": "Which of the following commands updates the linker cache of shared libraries?"
	,"choices": [
		"mkcache"
		,"soconfig"
		,"mkldconfig"
		,"lddconfig"
		,"ldconfig"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "E"
}
,{
	"question_number": 23
	,"question": "Which of the following commands lists all currently installed packages when using RPM package management?"
	,"choices": [
		"yum --query --all"
		,"yum --list --installed"
		,"rpm --query --all"
		,"rpm --listâ€“installed"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 24
	,"question": "Which of the following commands can be used to download the RPM package kernel without installing it?"
	,"choices": [
		"yum download --no-install kernel"
		,"yumdownloader kernel"
		,"rpm --download --package kernel"
		,"rpmdownload kernel"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 25
	,"question": "When using rpm --verify to check files created during the installation of RPM packages, which of the following information is taken into consideration? (Choose THREE correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"Timestamps"
		,"MD5 checksums"
		,"Inodes"
		,"File sizes"
		,"GnuPG signatures"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "ABD"
}
,{
	"question_number": 26
	,"question": "Which of the following is correct when talking about mount points?"
	,"choices": [
		"Every existing directory can be used as a mount point."
		,"Only empty directories can be used as a mount point."
		,"Directories need to have the SetUID flag set to be used as a mount point."
		,"Files within a directory are deleted when the directory is used as a mount point."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 27
	,"question": "Which function key is used to start Safe Mode in Windows NT?"
	,"choices": [
		"F10"
		,"F8"
		,"F6"
		,"Windows NT does not support Safe Mode"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 28
	,"question": "Which of the following environment variables overrides or extends the list of directories holding shared libraries?"
	,"choices": [
		"LD_LOAD_PATH"
		,"LD_LIB_PATH"
		,"LD_LIBRARY_PATH"
		,"LD_SHARE_PATH"
		,"LD_RUN_PATH"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 29
	,"question": "Which world-writable directory should be placed on a separate partition in order to prevent users from being able to fill up the / filesystem? (Specify the full path to the directory.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"/tmp"
		,"tmp"
		,"/var/tmp"
		,"/tmp/"
		,"/var/tmp/"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 30
	,"question": "Which RPM command will output the name of the package which supplied the file /etc/exports?"
	,"choices": [
		"rpm -F /etc/exports"
		,"rpm -qf /etc/exports"
		,"rpm -Kl /etc/exports"
		,"rpm -qp /etc/exports"
		,"rpm -qi /etc/exports"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 31
	,"question": "In which directory must definition files be placed to add additional repositories to yum?"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"/etc/yum.repos.d"
		,"/etc/yum.repos.d/"
		,"yum.repos.d"
		,"yum.repos.d/"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 32
	,"question": "What is the name of the main configuration file for GNU GRUB? (Specify the file name only without any path.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"menu.lst"
		,"grub.conf"
		,"grub.cfg"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 33
	,"question": "When removing a package, which of the following dpkg options will completely remove the files including configuration files?"
	,"choices": [
		"--clean"
		,"--delete"
		,"--purge"
		,"â€“remove"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 34
	,"question": "Which file should be edited to select the network locations from which Debian installation package files are loaded?"
	,"choices": [
		"/etc/dpkg/dpkg.cfg"
		,"/etc/apt/apt.conf"
		,"/etc/apt/apt.conf.d"
		,"/etc/apt/sources.list"
		,"/etc/dpkg/dselect.cfg"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 35
	,"question": "Which option to the yum command will update the entire system? (Specify ONLY the option name without any additional parameters.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"update"
		,"upgrade"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 36
	,"question": "Which command will disable swapping on a device? (Specify ONLY the command without any path or parameters.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"swapoff"
		,"/sbin/swapoff"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 37
	,"question": "Which Debian package management tool asks the configuration questions for a specific already installed package just as if the package were being installed for the first time? (Specify ONLY the command without any path or parameters.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"dpkg-reconfigure"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 38
	,"question": "Which of the following commands overwrites the bootloader located on /dev/sda without overwriting the partition table or any data following it?"
	,"choices": [
		"dd if=/dev/zero of=/dev/sda bs=512"
		,"dd if=/dev/zero of=/dev/sda bs=512 count=1"
		,"dd if=/dev/zero of=/dev/sda bs=440 count=1"
		,"dd if=/dev/zero of=/dev/sda bs=440"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 39
	,"question": "Which of the following commands can be used to create a USB storage media from a disk image?"
	,"choices": [
		"gdisk"
		,"dd"
		,"cc"
		,"fdisk"
		,"mount"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 40
	,"question": "In Bash, inserting 1>&2 after a command redirects"
	,"choices": [
		"standard error to standard input."
		,"standard input to standard error."
		,"standard output to standard error."
		,"standard error to standard output."
		,"standard output to standard input."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 41
	,"question": "What command will generate a list of user names from /etc/passwd along with their login shell?"
	,"choices": [
		"column -s : 1,7 /etc/passwd"
		,"chop -c 1,7 /etc/passwd"
		,"colrm 1,7 /etc/passwd"
		,"cut -d: -f1,7 /etc/passwd"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 42
	,"question": "In a nested directory structure, which find command line option would be used to restrict the command to searching down a particular number of subdirectories?"
	,"choices": [
		"-dirmax"
		,"-maxdepth"
		,"-maxlevels"
		,"-n"
		,"-s"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 43
	,"question": "Which of the following statements is correct regarding the command foo 1> bar?"
	,"choices": [
		"The stdout from the command foo is appended to the file bar."
		,"The stdout from the command foo overwrites the file bar."
		,"The command foo receives its stdin from the file bar."
		,"The command foo receives its stdin from the stdout of the command bar."
		,"The stderr from the command foo is saved to the file bar."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 44
	,"question": "Which of the following commands kills the process with the PID 123 but allows the process to \"clean up\" before exiting?"
	,"choices": [
		"kill -PIPE 123"
		,"kill -KILL 123"
		,"kill -STOP 123"
		,"kill -TERM 123"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 45
	,"question": "Which signal is missing from the following command that is commonly used to instruct a daemon to reinitialize itself, including reading configuration files? \\n\\n killall -s _______ daemon"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"HUP"
		,"SIGHUP"
		,"1"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 46
	,"question": "What is the maximum niceness value that a regular user can assign to a process with the nice command when executing a new process?"
	,"choices": [
		"9"
		,"19"
		,"49"
		,"99"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 47
	,"question": "Immediately after deleting 3 lines of text in vi and moving the cursor to a different line, which single character command will insert the deleted content below the current line?"
	,"choices": [
		"i (lowercase)"
		,"P (uppercase)"
		,"p (lowercase)"
		,"U (uppercase)"
		,"u (lowercase)"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 48
	,"question": "A user accidentally created the subdirectory \\dir in his home directory. Which of the following commands will remove that directory?"
	,"choices": [
		"rmdir '~/\\dir'"
		,"rmdir \\\"~/\\dir\\\""
		,"rmdir ~/'dir'"
		,"rmdir ~/\\dir"
		,"rmdir ~/\\\\dir"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "E"
}
,{
	"question_number": 49
	,"question": "In compliance with the FHS, in which of the directories are man pages found?"
	,"choices": [
		"/usr/share/man"
		,"/opt/man"
		,"/usr/doc/"
		,"/var/pkg/man"
		,"/var/man"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 50
	,"question": "Which of the following commands will send output from the program myapp to both standard output (stdout) and the file file1.log?"
	,"choices": [
		"cat < myapp | cat > file1.log"
		,"myapp 0>&1 | cat > file1.log"
		,"myapp | cat > file1.log"
		,"myapp | tee file1.log"
		,"tee myapp file1.log"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 51
	,"question": "What is the purpose of the Bash built-in export command?"
	,"choices": [
		"It allows disks to be mounted remotely."
		,"It runs a command as a process in a subshell."
		,"It makes the command history available to subshells."
		,"It sets up environment variables for applications."
		,"It shares NFS partitions for use by other systems on the network."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 52
	,"question": "What is the output of the following command? echo \"Hello World\" | tr -d aieou"
	,"choices": [
		"Hello World"
		,"eoo"
		,"Hll Wrld"
		,"eoo Hll Wrld"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 53
	,"question": "Which of the following characters can be combined with a separator string in order to read from the current input source until the separator string, which is on a separate line and without any trailing spaces, is reached?"
	,"choices": [
		"<<"
		,"<|"
		,"!<"
		,"&<"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 54
	,"question": "Which of the following commands will NOT update the modify timestamp on the file /tmp/myfile.txt?"
	,"choices": [
		"file /tmp/myfile.txt"
		,"echo \\\"Hello\\\" >/tmp/myfile.txt"
		,"sed -ie \\\"s/1/2/\\\" /tmp/myfile.txt"
		,"echo -n \\\"Hello\\\" >>/tmp/myfile.txt"
		,"touch /tmp/myfile.txt"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 55
	,"question": "What is the default nice level when a process is started using the nice command?"
	,"choices": [
		"-10"
		,"10"
		,"20"
		,"0"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 56
	,"question": "What is the default action of the split command on an input file?"
	,"choices": [
		"It will break the file into new files of 1,024 byte pieces each."
		,"It will break the file into new files of 1,000 line pieces each."
		,"It will break the file into new files of 1,024 kilobyte pieces each."
		,"It will break the file into new files that are no more than 5% of the size of the original file."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 57
	,"question": "What is the difference between the i and a commands of the vi editor?"
	,"choices": [
		"i (interactive) requires the user to explicitly switch between vi modes whereas a (automatic) switches modes automatically."
		,"i (insert) inserts text before the current cursor position whereas a (append) inserts text after the cursor."
		,"i (independent rows) starts every new line at the first character whereas a (aligned rows) keeps the indentation of the previous line."
		,"i (interrupt) temporarily suspends editing of a file to the background whereas a (abort) terminates editing."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 58
	,"question": "Which command displays a list of all background tasks running in the current shell? (Specify ONLY the command without any path or parameters.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"jobs"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 59
	,"question": "Which of the following commands moves and resumes in the background the last stopped shell job?"
	,"choices": [
		"run"
		,"bg"
		,"fg"
		,"back"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 60
	,"question": "What is the effect of the egrep command when the -v option is used?"
	,"choices": [
		"It enables color to highlight matching parts."
		,"It only outputs non-matching lines."
		,"It shows the command's version information."
		,"It changes the output order showing the last matching line first."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 61
	,"question": "What does the ? symbol within regular expressions represent?"
	,"choices": [
		"Match the preceding qualifier one or more times."
		,"Match the preceding qualifier zero or more times."
		,"Match the preceding qualifier zero or one times."
		,"Match a literal ? character."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 62
	,"question": "In the vi editor, how can commands such as moving the cursor or copying lines into the buffer be issued multiple times or applied to multiple rows?"
	,"choices": [
		"By using the command :repeat followed by the number and the command."
		,"By specifying the number right in front of a command such as 4l or 2yj."
		,"By selecting all affected lines using the shift and cursor keys before applying the command."
		,"By issuing a command such as :set repetition=4 which repeats every subsequent command 4 times."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 63
	,"question": "Which of the following files, located in the user home directory, is used to store the Bash history?"
	,"choices": [
		".bash_history"
		,".bash_histfile"
		,".history"
		,".bashrc_history"
		,".history_bash"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 64
	,"question": "Which Bash environment variable defines in which file the user history is stored when exiting a Bash process? (Specify ONLY the variable name.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"HISTFILE"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 65
	,"question": "Which of the following commands displays the contents of a gzip compressed tar archive?"
	,"choices": [
		"gzip archive.tgz | tar xvf"
		,"tar ztf archive.tgz"
		,"gzip -d archive.tgz | tar tvf"
		,"tar cf archive.tgz"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 66
	,"question": "Which grep command will print only the lines that do not end with a / in the file foo?"
	,"choices": [
		"grep '/$' foo"
		,"grep '/#' foo"
		,"grep -v '/$' foo"
		,"grep -v '/#' foo"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 67
	,"question": "Which of the following commands is used to change options and positional parameters for a running Bash?"
	,"choices": [
		"history"
		,"set"
		,"bashconf"
		,"setsh"
		,"envsetup"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 68
	,"question": "Which of the following commands replaces each occurrence of 'bob' in the file letter with 'Bob' and writes the result to the file newletter?"
	,"choices": [
		"sed '/bob/Bob' letter > newletter"
		,"sed s/bob/Bob/ letter < newletter"
		,"sed 's/bob/Bob' letter > newletter"
		,"sed 's/bob/Bob/g' letter > newletter"
		,"sed 's/bob, Bob/' letter > newletter"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 69
	,"question": "From a Bash shell, which of the following commands directly executes the instruction from the file /usr/local/bin/runme.sh without starting a subshell? (Please select TWO answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"source /usr/local/bin/runme.sh"
		,". /usr/local/bin/runme.sh"
		,"/bin/bash /usr/local/bin/runme.sh"
		,"/usr/local/bin/runme.sh"
		,"run /usr/local/bin/runme.sh"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AB"
}
,{
	"question_number": 70
	,"question": "Regarding the command: nice -5 /usr/bin/prog Which of the following statements is correct?"
	,"choices": [
		"/usr/bin/prog is executed with a nice level of -5."
		,"/usr/bin/prog is executed with a nice level of 5."
		,"/usr/bin/prog is executed with a priority of -5."
		,"/usr/bin/prog is executed with a priority of 5."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 71
	,"question": "Which shell command is used to continue background execution of a suspended command?"
	,"choices": [
		"&"
		,"bg"
		,"cont"
		,"exec"
		,":&"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 72
	,"question": "Which of the following shell redirections will write standard output and standard error output to a file named filename?"
	,"choices": [
		"2>&1 >filename"
		,">filename 2>&1"
		,"1>&2>filename"
		,">>filename"
		,"1&2>filename"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 73
	,"question": "In the vi editor, which of the following commands will copy the current line into the vi buffer?"
	,"choices": [
		"c"
		,"cc"
		,"1c"
		,"yy"
		,"1y"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 74
	,"question": "Which of the following sequences in the vi editor saves the opened document and exits the editor? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"esc ZZ"
		,"ctrl :w!"
		,"esc zz"
		,"esc :wq!"
		,"ctrl XX"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AD"
}
,{
	"question_number": 75
	,"question": "When starting a program with the nice command without any additional parameters, which nice level is set for the resulting process?"
	,"choices": [
		"-10"
		,"0"
		,"10"
		,"20"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 76
	,"question": "Which of the following commands will reduce all consecutive spaces down to a single space?"
	,"choices": [
		"tr '\\s' ' ' < a.txt > b.txt"
		,"tr -c ' ' < a.txt > b.txt"
		,"tr -d ' ' < a.txt > b.txt"
		,"tr -r ' ' '\\n' < a.txt > b.txt"
		,"tr -s ' ' < a.txt > b.txt"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "E"
}
,{
	"question_number": 77
	,"question": "Which character, added to the end of a command, runs that command in the background as a child process of the current shell?"
	,"choices": [
		"!"
		,"+"
		,"&"
		,"%"
		,"#"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 78
	,"question": "Which of the following commands will print the last 10 lines of a text file to the standard output?"
	,"choices": [
		"cat -n 10 filename"
		,"dump -n 10 filename"
		,"head -n 10 filename"
		,"tail -n 10 filename"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 79
	,"question": "Which of the following commands prints a list of usernames (first column) and their primary group (fourth column) from the /etc/passwd file?"
	,"choices": [
		"fmt -f 1,4 /etc/passwd"
		,"split -c 1,4 /etc/passwd"
		,"cut -d : -f 1,4 /etc/passwd"
		,"paste -f 1,4 /etc/passwd"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 80
	,"question": "Which of the following signals is sent to a process when the key combination CTRL+C is pressed on the keyboard?"
	,"choices": [
		"SIGTERM"
		,"SIGINT"
		,"SIGSTOP"
		,"SIGKILL"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 81
	,"question": "What happens after issuing the command vi without any additional parameters?"
	,"choices": [
		"vi starts and loads the last file used and moves the cursor to the position where vi was when it last exited."
		,"vi starts and requires the user to explicitly either create a new or load an existing file."
		,"vi exits with an error message as it cannot be invoked without a file name to operate on."
		,"vi starts in command mode and opens a new empty file."
		,"vi starts and opens a new file which is filled with the content of the vi buffer if the buffer contains text."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 82
	,"question": "Which of the following command sets the Bash variable named TEST with the content FOO?"
	,"choices": [
		"set TEST=\\\"FOO\\\""
		,"TEST = \\\"FOO\\\""
		,"var TEST=\\\"FOO\\\""
		,"TEST=\\\"FOO\\\""
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 83
	,"question": "Which variable defines the directories in which a Bash shell searches for executable commands?"
	,"choices": [
		"BASHEXEC"
		,"BASHRC"
		,"PATH"
		,"EXECPATH"
		,"PATHRC"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 84
	,"question": "Which of the following commands determines the type of a file by using a definition database file which contains information about all common file types?"
	,"choices": [
		"magic"
		,"type"
		,"file"
		,"pmagic"
		,"hash"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 85
	,"question": "Which command is used in a Linux environment to create a new directory? (Specify ONLY the command without any path or parameters.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"mkdir"
		,"/usr/bin/mkdir"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 86
	,"question": "Which of the following commands prints all files and directories within the /tmp directory or its subdirectories which are also owned by the user root? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"find /tmp -uid root -print"
		,"find -path /tmp -uid root"
		,"find /tmp -user root -print"
		,"find /tmp -user root"
		,"find -path /tmp -user rootâ€“print"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "CD"
}
,{
	"question_number": 87
	,"question": "When running the command sed -e \"s/a/b/\" /tmp/file >/tmp/file While /tmp/file contains data, why is /tmp/file empty afterwards?"
	,"choices": [
		"The file order is incorrect. The destination file must be mentioned before the command to ensure redirection."
		,"The command sed did not match anything in that file therefore the output is empty."
		,"When the shell establishes the redirection it overwrites the target file before the redirected command starts and opens it for reading."
		,"Redirection for shell commands do not work using the > character. It only works using the | character instead."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 88
	,"question": "When given the following command line. echo \"foo bar\" | tee bar | cat Which of the following output is created?"
	,"choices": [
		"cat"
		,"foo bar"
		,"tee bar"
		,"bar"
		,"foo"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 89
	,"question": "Which of the following commands can be used to determine how long the system has been running? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"uptime"
		,"up"
		,"top"
		,"uname -u"
		,"timeâ€“up"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AC"
}
,{
	"question_number": 90
	,"question": "Which of the following are valid stream redirection operators within Bash? (Choose THREE correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"<"
		,"<<<"
		,">"
		,">>>"
		,"%>"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "ABC"
}
,{
	"question_number": 91
	,"question": "After successfully creating a hard link called bar to the ordinary file foo, foo is deleted from the filesystem. Which of the following describes the resulting situation?"
	,"choices": [
		"foo and bar would both be removed."
		,"foo would be removed while bar would remain accessible."
		,"foo would be removed. bar would still exist but would be unusable."
		,"Both foo and bar would remain accessible."
		,"The user is prompted whether bar should be removed, too."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 92
	,"question": "After moving data to a new filesystem, how can the former path of the data be kept intact in order to avoid reconfiguration of existing applications? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"By creating an ACL redirection from the old to the new path of the data."
		,"By creating a hard link from the old to the new path of the data."
		,"By creating a symbolic link from the old to the new path of the data."
		,"By running the command touch on the old path."
		,"By mounting the new filesystem on the original path of the data."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "CE"
}
,{
	"question_number": 93
	,"question": "Which of the following commands changes the ownership of file.txt to the user dan and the group staff?"
	,"choices": [
		"chown dan/staff file.txt"
		,"chown dan:staff file.txt"
		,"chown -u dan -g staff file.txt"
		,"chown dan -g staff file.txt"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 94
	,"question": "Which of the following commands makes /bin/foo executable by everyone but writable only by its owner?"
	,"choices": [
		"chmod u=rwx,go=rx /bin/foo"
		,"chmod o+rwx,a+rx /bin/foo"
		,"chmod 577 /bin/foo"
		,"chmod 775 /bin/foo"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 95
	,"question": "Which of the following commands can be used to search for the executable file foo when it has been placed in a directory not included in $PATH?"
	,"choices": [
		"apropos"
		,"which"
		,"find"
		,"query"
		,"whereis"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 96
	,"question": "What does the command mount -a do?"
	,"choices": [
		"It ensures that all file systems listed with the option noauto in /etc/fstab are mounted."
		,"It shows all mounted file systems that have been automatically mounted."
		,"It opens an editor with root privileges and loads /etc/fstab for editing."
		,"It ensures that all file systems listed with the option auto in /etc/fstab are mounted."
		,"It ensures that all file systems listed in /etc/fstab are mounted regardless of their options."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 97
	,"question": "Which of the following settings for umask ensures that new files have the default permissions -rwr----- ?"
	,"choices": [
		"0017"
		,"0640"
		,"0038"
		,"0027"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 98
	,"question": "Which of the following is the device file name for the second partition on the only SCSI drive?"
	,"choices": [
		"/dev/hda1"
		,"/dev/sda2"
		,"/dev/sd0a2"
		,"/dev/sd1p2"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 99
	,"question": "In order to display all currently mounted filesystems, which of the following commands could be used? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"cat /proc/self/mounts"
		,"free"
		,"mount"
		,"lsmounts"
		,"cat /proc/filesystems"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AC"
}
,{
	"question_number": 100
	,"question": "Which of the following commands can be used to locate programs and their corresponding man pages and configuration files?"
	,"choices": [
		"dirname"
		,"which"
		,"basename"
		,"query"
		,"whereis"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "E"
}
,{
	"question_number": 101
	,"question": "Which of the following commands changes the number of days before the ext3 filesystem on /dev/sda1 has to run through a full filesystem check while booting?"
	,"choices": [
		"tune2fs -d 200 /dev/sda1"
		,"tune2fs -c 200 /dev/sda1"
		,"tune2fs -i 200 /dev/sda1"
		,"tune2fs -n 200 /dev/sda1"
		,"tune2fs --days 200 /dev/sda1"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 102
	,"question": "Which type of filesystem is created by mkfs when it is executed with the block device name only and without any additional parameters?"
	,"choices": [
		"ext2"
		,"ext3"
		,"ext4"
		,"XFS"
		,"VFAT"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 103
	,"question": "How many fields are in a syntactically correct line of /etc/fstab?"
	,"choices": [
		"3"
		,"4"
		,"5"
		,"6"
		,"7"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 104
	,"question": "Which command is used to create and initialize the files used to store quota information? (Specify ONLY the command without any path or parameters.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"quotacheck"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 105
	,"question": "Which of the following file permissions belong to a symbolic link?"
	,"choices": [
		"-rwxrwxrwx"
		,"+rwxrwxrwx"
		,"lrwxrwxrwx"
		,"srwxrwxrwx"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 106
	,"question": "Creating a hard link to an ordinary file returns an error. What could be the reason for this?"
	,"choices": [
		"The source file is hidden."
		,"The source file is read-only."
		,"The source file is a shell script."
		,"The source file is already a hard link."
		,"The source and the target are on different filesystems."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "E"
}
,{
	"question_number": 107
	,"question": "Which of the following commands creates an ext3 filesystem on /dev/sdb1? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"/sbin/mke2fs -j /dev/sdb1"
		,"/sbin/mkfs -t ext3 /dev/sdb1"
		,"/sbin/mkfs -c ext3 /dev/sdb1"
		,"/sbin/mke3fs -j /dev/sdb1"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AB"
}
,{
	"question_number": 108
	,"question": "Which of the following commands will change the quota for a specific user?"
	,"choices": [
		"edquota"
		,"repquota"
		,"quota -e"
		,"quota"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "A"
}
,{
	"question_number": 109
	,"question": "Which utility would be used to change how often a filesystem check is performed on an ext2 filesystem without losing any data stored on that filesystem?"
	,"choices": [
		"mod2fs"
		,"fsck"
		,"tune2fs"
		,"mke2fs"
		,"fixe2fs"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 110
	,"question": "Which of the following Linux filesystems preallocates a fixed number of inodes at the filesystem's make/creation time and does NOT generate them as needed? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"ext3"
		,"JFS"
		,"ext2"
		,"XFS"
		,"procfs"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "AC"
}
,{
	"question_number": 111
	,"question": "What is the purpose of the Filesystem Hierarchy Standard?"
	,"choices": [
		"It is a security model used to ensure files are organized according to their permissions and accessibility."
		,"It provides unified tools to create, maintain and manage multiple filesystems in a common way."
		,"It defines a common internal structure of inodes for all compliant filesystems."
		,"It is a distribution neutral description of locations of files and directories."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 112
	,"question": "Which umask value will result in the default access permissions of 600 (rw-------) for files and 700 (rwx------) for directories? (Specify only the numerical umask value.)"
	,"is_fill_in_the_blank": true
	,"fill_answers": [
		"0077"
		,"077"
	]
}
,{
	"question_number": 113
	,"question": "Instead of supplying an explicit device in /etc/fstab for mounting, what other options may be used to identify the intended partition? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"FIND"
		,"ID"
		,"LABEL"
		,"NAME"
		,"UUID"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "CE"
}
,{
	"question_number": 114
	,"question": "After running the command umount /mnt, the following error message is displayed: umount: /mnt: device is busy. What is a common reason for this message?"
	,"choices": [
		"The kernel has not finished flushing disk writes to the mounted device."
		,"A user has a file open in the /mnt directory."
		,"Another file system still contains a symlink to a file inside /mnt."
		,"The files in /mnt have been scanned and added to the locate database."
		,"The kernel thinks that a process is about to open a file in /mnt for reading."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 115
	,"question": "What does the command mount -a do?"
	,"choices": [
		"It mounts all available filesystems onto the current directory."
		,"It shows all mounted filesystems."
		,"It mounts all user mountable filesystems for the current user."
		,"It mounts all filesystems listed in /etc/fstab which have the option auto set."
		,"It mounts all filesystems listed in /etc/fstab which have the option noauto set."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "D"
}
,{
	"question_number": 116
	,"question": "Which of the following commands set the sticky bit for the directory /tmp? (Choose TWO correct answers.)"
	,"choices": [
		"chmod +s /tmp"
		,"chmod +t /tmp"
		,"chmod 1775 /tmp"
		,"chmod 4775 /tmp"
		,"chmod 2775 /tmp"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "BC"
}
,{
	"question_number": 117
	,"question": "Which of the following commands can be used to display the inode number of a given file?"
	,"choices": [
		"inode"
		,"ls"
		,"ln"
		,"cp"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "B"
}
,{
	"question_number": 118
	,"question": "Which of the following commands shows the definition of a given shell command?"
	,"choices": [
		"where"
		,"stat"
		,"type"
		,"case"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 119
	,"question": "What do the permissions -rwSr-xr-x mean for a binary file when it is executed as a command?"
	,"choices": [
		"The command is SetUID and it will be executed with the effective rights of the owner."
		,"The command will be executed with the effective rights of the group instead of the owner."
		,"The execute flag is not set for the owner. Therefore the SetUID flag is ignored."
		,"The command will be executed with the effective rights of the owner and group."
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
,{
	"question_number": 120
	,"question": "Which of the following pieces of information of an existing file is changed when a hard link pointing to that file is created?"
	,"choices": [
		"File size"
		,"Modify timestamp"
		,"Link count"
		,"Inode number"
		,"Permissions"
	]
	,"correct_answers": "C"
}
]}
